# Software Engineer

# Alex Cummaudo

+61 0420 553 685 alexcu@me.com http://alexcu.me

#### **Objective**

With industry experience in the education, research and commercial sectors as a software engineer and teaching assistant, I am currently pursuing an undergraduate degree program in Computer Science and anticipate to graduate in 2016.

I help discover creative solutions to problems unsolved and envision seamlessness in products that enrich people's lives and connect us together. Having a thirst for knowledge and by keeping myself at the forefront of innovation, I aim to develop great ideas into great products.

#### Skills **Core Strengths**

Web Application Development, Mobile Application Development, RESTful API Development, Concurrent Program Design, Teaching, UI/UX Design and Prototyping, Website Administration

#### **Technical Skills**

AngularJS, Node.js, iOS/Objective-C/Swift, JavaScript/CoffeeScript/DOM, SCSS/LESS/CSS3, Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, ETFX, C#/.NET, C/C++, Pascal

#### Software

Git, AWS, Apache2, Nginx, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Xcode, Xamarin, Coda 2, Trello, Pixelmator, Lucidchart

#### Experience

#### **Associate Developer**

Aug 2015-Present

SEEK Ltd., Melbourne

SEEK is Australia's largest jobs, employment, career and recruitment website.

- Development of search relevance ranking tools to improve search quality on SEEK's website.
- Focus on scalable cloud computing architecture with Amazon Web Services.
- Experience with continuous deployment and test-driven development environments.

#### **Software Engineer**

Aug 2014-Aug 2015

Swinburne NICTA Software Innovation Lab (SSIL), Hawthorn

SSIL delivers research-driven high-impact software solutions and is partnered with NICTA.

- · Developed projects across various domains including fleet visualiser (via Google Maps) and management software, website development, and a web-based IDE front-end (http://rappt.io/).
- Web Application Development using AngularJS, Middleman, Node.js; iOS App Development in Objective-C.
- Experience in an Agile development environment; engaging in stand-ups and sprints.

#### **Introduction to Programming Tutor**

Mar 2014-Aug 2015

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

Teaching a first-year introductory programming unit taken by all students in technology-related fields.

- Delivering learning content to tutorials of 25 students via interactive sessions mixed with liveprogramming, concept discussions, running group work activities and one-to-one feedback
- · Assisting students understand fundamental programming concepts by assessing and providing feedback on weekly submitted work from students
- Preparing students for tests by running group exercises that allowed students to learn off each other; engaging student's learning by giving them the opportunity to work together
- · Working with an enthusiastic team to gather teaching ideas and methods and contributing at weekly meetings, writing and sharing weekly reflections on classes

#### **Web Application Developer (Pro Brono)**

Winter Break-2014

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

Development of a modern Learning Management System, Doubtfire.

- · Building a large-scale web application utilised in tutoring position for student progress tracking (http://doubtfire.ict.swin.edu.au)
- Developing front-end development with Bootstrap and AngularJS
- Back-end development using Ruby on Rails, PostGres and Grape API

#### UI/UX Developer

Mar 2014-Aug 2014

LeadSoftware, Melbourne

LeadSoftware specialises in complete tracking, logistic and dispatch systems.

- Lead UX and UI design for a large-scale on-board taxi system currently in deployment in a large taxi fleet
- Strong interaction with development team to explain prototypes and mock-ups developed and discuss feedback on implemented designs
- Prototyping for apps on iOS and Android using a mix of whiteboard, Pixelmator and FluidUI techniques

#### **Programming Help Desk Staff**

Aug 2013-Dec 2013

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

Providing assistance in out-of-class sessions with students.

- Assisting students learn syntax of C, Pascal, PHP, JavaScript
- Explaining programming concepts to students and working through logic problems in a enthusiastic and approachable environment
- Help Desk initiative and staff commended by the Australian Computer Society

#### Education

# **Bachelor of Science (Professional Software Development)**

Aug 2013-Present

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

High Distinction Average (GPA 4.0). Perfect marks of 100 in Introductory and and Object-Oriented Programming units; near-perfect marks of 98 in iOS Development and Usability.

#### **Key Disciplines:**

- Web and iOS Application Design and Development
- Concurrent Programming
- Data Structure Theory
- Development of Programming Languages
- User Interface and Experience Design
- Database Design and Programming

#### **Victorian Certificate of Education (VCE)**

Feb 2010-Nov 2012

Parade College, Bundoora

Australian Tertiary Admittance Ranking (ATAR) of 98.00 of 99.95.

#### Awards

#### **Certificate of Achievement Awards**

November 2014, July 2015

Highest Achieving Student with the highest marks in nine subjects

Awarded by Prof. John Wilson - Executive Dean, Faculty of Science, Engineering and Technology, Swinburne University.

#### Certificate of Appreciation Award

1 Nov 2013

Swinburne ICT Student Ambassador Program

Awarded by Prof. Leon Sterling - Dean, Faculty of ICT, Swinburne University.

#### Vice Chancellor's Scholarship

31 Mar 2013

On outstanding academic excellence

Awarded by Prof. Linda Kristjanson - Vice Chancellor, Swinburne University.

**Dux Award** 8 Feb 2013

On achieving excellent VCE results and gaining one of the highest ATAR scores in the college. Awarded by Dr. Denis Moore - Principal, Parade College.

## Extra Curricular

# University

- Member of the Swinburne Tinkerers Guild
- Open Day Volunteering—discussing and advocating Swinburne degrees
- Spokesperson for Swinburne's Faculty of Information Technology
- Mentor for VCE students enrolled in Swinburne's Higher Education Studies within the VCE program

### Hobbies and interests

- · Hiking and jogging
- Antique computing
- Casual indie game developer at Paperbox Studios

#### Referrals

Dr. Rajesh Vasa Head of R&D Swinburne Software Innovation Lab +61 435 016 006 rvasa@swin.edu.au

Dr. Andrew Cain Senior Lecturer Swinburne University +61 03 9214 5324 acain@swin.edu.au

Mr. Appu Babu Iteration Manager SEEK Ltd. +61 403 876 529 appubabu@gmail.com